

IVÁN IGLESIAS

Data Engineer

- @ ivaniglesias500@protonmail.ch
- **J** +593-9883-95742
- Quito, Ecuador

- in ivan-iglesias-6192351ba/
- Jefe21054
- linktr.ee/ivan_iglesias

SKILLS

Python PySpark SQL PostgreSQL SQL Server

API REST Stratio AWS

Azure MongoDB Linux

Docker Java JavaScript

Typescript HTML5

CSS3 SCRUM Jira

MATLAB Excel LATEX

THAT LAD LACET LIEA

MicroPython Arduino

C Team work

Continuous Learner

Troubleshooting

Technical Support

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Proficiency / B2 Portuguese: Basic / A1

REFERENCES

Communications Major Pablo Albán, Ecuadorian

IT Dept. Chief at AGFT pfalban@gmail.com +593-9927-21499

Eng. Daniel Altamirano, PhD.

Research Professor at UFA - ESPE

cdaltamirano@espe.edu.ec +593-9950-71081

Eng. Pablo Molineros

Data Scientist at Banco Pichincha.

alexmolineros15@gmail.com +593-9825-36644

ABOUT ME

I'm a Data Engineer (Python, SQL, PySpark, Stratio, AWS, Azure, PostgreSQL, Oracle, SQL Server). I have experience working with Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence (Generative Pre-Trained Transformers, Large Language Models, Text, Signals and Image generation) and Network Engineering with Design, Routing, Switching, Wireless and RF Networks and have multiple skills in Electronics and IoT development languages (MicroPython, Arduino, C). Good handle of technical projects applying Agile Methodologies.

EXPERIENCE

IT Department Technical Assistant | Academia de Guerra del Ejército (AGFT)

Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

- Sangolquí, Ecuador
- Provided support to any technical problem that may arise with any electronic or telecommunications system through the IT department, reducing user complaints by 10%.

RF Technician | Gibellcomm S.A.

Mar 2023 - Jun 2023

- Quito, Ecuador
- Single Site Verification and Drive Test for GSM, UMTS and LTE in Mobile Networks.

Data Engineer Trainee | Banco Pichincha C.A.

Jun 2023 - Present

- Quito, Ecuador
- I worked in the automation of Outbound Calls ETL with Azure DevOps and Documentation.
- I developed a chatbot focused on agricultural information for the Bank's sectors cell as part of the Trainee Program's project.
- I supported Bank's Human Resources needs through an ETL that processes survey responses for external employees.
- Currently I am helping in the automation of a process of the Customer Service Unit (UAC).

EDUCATION

Engineer's Degree, Electronics and Telecommunications | Universidad de las Fuerzas Armadas – ESPE

Mar 2017 - Aug 2023

- Sangolquí, Ecuador
- **Degree's Project:** Implementation of a Cotopaxi volcano microearthquake classifier system based on Deep Learning techniques.

PROJECTS

PyBot-ChatGPT | 😱



A custom chatbot programmed with Python and the Chat-GPT API, trained with text with information of AI and Machine Learning.

Implementation of a Cotopaxi volcano microearthquake classifier system based on Deep Learning techniques

- **a** Aug 2023
- Volcanic Data extraction, transformation and load for availability into a database.
- Development of Stacked Autoencoder and Deep Neural Network models for data processing.
- Data and Results analysis through 5 performance metrics: accuracy, precision, specificity, sensitivity and Balanced Error Rate.

IglesiasShop E-Commerce



Mar 2023

Complete E-Commerce project, created with Django and Python, deployed with Docker. It has professional design and PayPal integrated payments.

Django REST API | 🔗



May 2023

Point of Sales backend API REST developed with Django and Django REST Framework (DRF), documented using Swagger and deployed with Docker.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Introduction to Data Science | Cisco | 6

Apr 2023

Networking Basics | Cisco | 🔗

Apr 2023

Linux desde cero | EDteam | 🔗

ä Jun 2023

Introducción a DevOps | EDteam | 🔗

i Jun 2023

Domina Python | EDteam | 🔗

Apr 2023

Desarrollo web con Django 2023 | EDteam | 🔗

Mar 2023

Desarrollo web avanzado con Flask | EDteam | 🔗

Apr 2023

Curso de Introducción a la Terminal y Línea de Comandos | Platzi | 🔗

Apr 2023

MAS-ROS: Introducción a MikroTik RouterOS | Academy Xperts

May 2023

• Credential ID: MSROS-1683338366-1202-3055

MAS-WOS Introducción a Wireless de MikroTik | Academy Xperts | 🔗

| *&*

Feb 2023

• Credential ID: MASWOS-1676041668-1828-3055

MAE-RAV-ROS Introducción a Ruteo Avanzado con MikroTik RouterOS | Academy Xperts | •

i Jan 2023

• Credential ID: MERAVROS-1673232607-2156-3055